Finding Aid for the Charles S. Mitchell Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- (1946)
  - (Box 3)
    Gypsy Lady (a period piece created to re-introduce music by Victor Herbert)(combines melodies of 2 of his most distinguished operettas, “The Fortune Teller” and “The Serenade”) (Musical adaptation and Choral arrangements by Arthur Kay) (book by Henry Myers) & (new lyrics by Robert Wright and George Forrest) Century Theatre, NY
    Hamlet by William Shakespeare Nashville Community Playhouse
    Hosea: A Cantata by F. Arthur Henkel, given Sunday, October 6, 1946--8 p.m. at Christ’s Church, Nashville, Tennessee
    Jooss Ballett, Artistic Director Kurt Jooss, Performed Thursday, November 7, 1946--8:15 p.m. Ryman Auditorium, N
    Nashville Community Playhouse Announcement of Twelfth Season: 1946-47
    Old Vic Theatre Company (Henry IV, Part 1; Henry IV, Part 2; Uncle Vanya; Oedipus, English version by W. B. Yeats; The Critic by William Sheridan), presented May 6 to June 15 (First American Engagement of Old Vic) New Century Theatre, NY
    State of the Union by Howard Lindsay and Russel Crouse Hudson Theatre, NY
    Swan Song by Ben Hecht and Charles MacArthur Booth Theatre, NY
    Tonight at Eight-Thirty by Noel Coward Nashville Community Playhouse
- (1947)
  - (Box 3)
    All My Sons by Arthur Miller (staged by Elia Kazan) Coronet Theatre, NY
    Born Yesterday by Garson Kanin Lyceum Theatre, NY
    Brigadoon (book & lyrics) by Alan Jay Lerner and (music) by Frederick Loewe Ziegfeld Theatre, NY
    Call Me Mister (music & lyrics) by Harold Rome Blackstone Theatre, C
    Command Decision by William Wister Haines Fulton Theatre, NY
    Cradle Snatchers by Russell G. Medcraft and Norma Mitchell Nashville Community Playhouse
    Duet for Two Hands by Mary Hayley Bell Booth Theatre, NY
    The Glass Menagerie by Tennessee Williams Nashville Community Playhouse
    The Happiest Days of Your Life by John Dighton Apollo Theatre London, England
    Happy Birthday (2) by Anita Loos (starring Helen Hayes) Rogers and Hammerstein Production Broadhurst Theatre, NY
    The Heiress by Ruth and Augustus Goetz (starring Basil Rathbone) Biltmore Theatre, NY
    How I Wonder by Donald Ogden Stewart Hudson Theatre, NY
    The Iceman Cometh by Eugene O’Neill Studebaker Theatre, C
    The Importance of Being Earnest by Oscar Wilde Nashville Community Playhouse
    Joan of Lorraine by Maxwell Anderson Nashville Community Playhouse
    Nashville Symphony Orchestra Program for Tuesday, October 28, 1947
    Of Thee I Sing (music) by George Gershwin and (lyrics) by Ira Gershwin Nashville Community Playhouse
    Rain by John Colton and Clemence Randolph Nashville Community Playhouse
    The Taming of the Shrew by William Shakespeare Nashville Community Playhouse
    The Tempest by William Shakespeare Nashville Community Playhouse
    Under the Counter by Arthur Macrae (music) by Manning Sherwin and (lyrics) by Harold Purcell Sam. S. Shubert Theatre, NY
- (1948)
  - (Box 4)
    A Streetcar Named Desire by Tennessee Williams (Elia Kazan production) Ethel Barrymore Theatre NY
    Charley’s Aunt by Brandon Thomas Nashville Community Playhouse N
    Edward, My Son by Robert Morly and Noel Langley Martin Beck Theatre NY
    Inside U.S.A. (lyrics and music) by Howard Dietz and Arthur Schwartz Majestic Theatre NY
    Magdalena by Heitor Villa-Lobos (pattern and lyrics) by Robert Wright and George Forrest (book) by Frederick Hazlitt Brennan and Homer Curran Ziegfeld Theatre NY
    Mister Roberts by Thomas Heggen and Joshua Logan Alvin Theatre NY
    Nashville Symphony Orchestra Program for Tuesday, March 29, 1948 N
    The Shanghai Gesture by John Colton Nashville Community Playhouse N
    Radio City Music Hall Program for week beginning Thursday, Oct. 7, 1948 NY
    The Respectful Prostitute by Jean-Paul Sartre (adapted from French by Eva Walas) together with Hope is the Thing with Feathers by Richard Harrity Cort Theatre NY
    Summer and Smoke by Tennessee Williams Music Box NY
    The Voice of the Turtle by John Van Druten Nashville Community Playhouse N
- (1949)
  - (Box 4)
    Anne of the Thousand Days by Maxwell Anderson Schubert Theatre NY
    Happy Birthday by Anita Loos Nashville Community Playhouse N
    Les Sylphides (ballet music) by Frederic Chopin Sadler’s Wells Ballet London
    Macbeth by William Shakespeare Shakespeare Memorial Theatre Stratfox -upon- Avon
    The Madwoman of Chaillot by Jean Giraudoux Belasco Theatre NY
    A Midsummer Night’s Dream by William Shakespeare Shakespeare Memorial Theatre Stratfox -upon- Avon
    Roberta by Alice Duer Miller Nashville Community Playhouse N
    The Spider by Fulton Oursler and Lowell Brentano Nashville Community Playhouse N
    The Heiress by Ruth and Augustus Goetz Theatre Royal London
    Program for Old Vic Theatre Company, 1948-1949 Season New Theatre London
    Ridgeway’s Late Joys by Peter Ridgeway and Leonard Sachs Villiers Street London
    A Streetcar Named Desire by Tennessee Williams Ethel Barrymore Theatre NY
    That Lady by Kate O’Brien Martin Beck Theatre NY
    Menu from Lucerne, Switzerland
    Shakespeare Memorial Theatre Programme, April 16-June 11
    Edinburgh International Festival of Music and Drama Program, August 21-September 11
- (1950)
  - (Box 4)
    Born Yesterday by Garson Kanin Nashville Community Playhouse N
    Henry IV by Shakespeare Sewanee, Tennessee
    The Madwoman of Chaillot by Jean Giraudoux Nashville Community Playhouse N
    Romeo and Juliet by Shakespeare Nashville Community Playhouse N
    The Royal Family by George S. Kaufman and Edna Ferber Nashville Community Playhouse N
    Nashville Symphony Orchestra Program for April 3 Ryman Auditorium N
- (1951)
  - (Box 4)
    Finian’s Rainbow (book) by E. Y. Harburg and Fred Saidy, (lyrics) by E. Y. Harburg, (Music) by Burton Lane Nashville Community Playhouse N
    Season in the Sun by Wolcott Gibbs Cort Theatre NY
    The Players Bulletin, Spring 1951
- (1952)
  - (Box 4)
    The Red Mill by Victor Herbert and Henry Blossom Nashville Community Playhouse N
- (1954)
  - (Box 4)
    The Dark is Light Enough by Christopher Fry Aldwych Theatre London
    Les Sylphides, The Firebird, and La Boutique Fantasque Sadler’s Wells Ballet London
    The Boy Friend by Sandy Wilson Wyndam’s Theatre London
- Addenda (1951)
  - (Box 4)
    Victoria Regina 100th Production of Nashville Community Playhouse Nashville Community Playhouse N
- (1955)
  - (Box 4)
    The Bad Seed by Maxwell Anderson Aldwych Theatre London
    The Shadow of Doubt by Norman King (2 copies) Saville Theatre London
- (1960)
  - (Box 4)
    Fings Ain’t Wot They Used T’Be by Frank Norman and Lionel Bart Garrick Theatre London
    The Merchant of Venice by Shakespeare Old Vic Company Bristol
    Romeo and Juliet by Shakespeare Old Vic Company Bristol
    Twelfth Night by Shakespeare Old Vic Company Bristol
    Orpheus in the Underworld by Jacques Offenbach and Hector Cremieux Sadler’s Wells Theatre London
- (1961)
  - (Box 4)
    The Bishop’s Bonfire by Sean O’Casey Mermaid Theatre London
    Five Plus One by Steven Vinaver and Carl Davis Royal Lyceum Theatre Edinburgh
    Il Barbiere di Siviglia by Gioacchino Rossini King’s Theatre Edinburgh
    King John by Shakespeare Assembly Hall Edinburgh
    Let Wives Tak Tent by Robert Kemp Gateway Theatre Edinburgh
    ‘Tis Pity She’s a Whore by John Ford Mermaid Theatre London
    The Tragical History of Dr. Faustus by Christopher Marlowe Assembly Hall Edinburgh
    Wildest Dreams by Dorothy Reynolds and Julian Slade Vaudeville Theatre London
    Four Programs for the Edinburgh International Festival
    Program for the Mermaid Theatre, June-September
    “An Evening with Juliette Greco” Royal Lyceum Theatre London
- (1963)
  - (Box 4)
    Camelot by Alan Jay Lerner and Frederick Loewe War Memorial Opera House San Francisco
    The Stephen Foster Story by Paul Green My Old Kentucky Home Bardstown, K
- (1958)
  - (Box 4)
    *Playbill for Auntie Mame, June 9, 1958 Broadhurst Theatre NY
- No Date
  - (Box 4)
    Aladdin and his Wonderful Lamp Little Theatre N
    Alice in Wonderland Little Theatre N
    Candida by George Bernard Shaw Little Theatre N
    On Approval by Frederick Lonsdale Little Theatre N
    The Racket by Bartlett Cormack Little Theatre N
    The Wild Duck by Henrick Ibsen Little Theatre N
    Charley’s Aunt by Brandon Thomas Little Theatre N
    Hay Fever by Noel Coward Little Theatre N
    Liliom by Franz Molnar Little Theatre N
    Sun-Up by Lula Vollmer Little Theatre N
    The Vortex by Noel Coward Little Theatre N
    Children of the Moon by Martin Flavin Little Theatre N
    Craig’s Wife by George Kelly Little Theatre Guild Bellamy Players N
    The Dover Road by A. A. Milne Little Theatre N
    Erstwhile Susan by Marian De Forest Little Theatre N
    Loose Ankles by Sam Janney Little Theatre N
    Recital by Helen Jepson Metropolitan Opera Association N
    Anthonv and Cleopatra by Shakespeare starring Katherine Cornell
    Petticoat Influence by Neil Grant starring Helen Hayes Lyceum Theatre
    Tomorrow and Tomorrow by Philip Barry Henry Miller’s Theatre NY
    Tristan et Isolde by Richard Wagner Theatre Nat. de l’Opera Paris
    Dark of the Moon: A Legend with Music by Howard Richardson and William Berney NY
    Sketchbook on Cornelia Otis Skinner
    Children of Earth by Alice Brown Birm’gham
    Daphne Laureola by James Birdie Wyndham’s Theatre London
    The School for Scandal by Richard Brinsley Sheridan Old Vic Theatre Company, New Theatre London
    September Tide by Daphne du Maurier Aldwych Theatre
    Together Again by Jack Hylton Victoria Palace London
    Wappin’ Wharf: A Frightful Comedy of Pirates by Charles S. Brooks Jefferson Theatre N
    Sketch book on Eva Le Gallienne
    Two musical performances by “The Saltire Group”
    Scotland in the Robin’s Flight performed by Elizabeth Seton
    A La Carte by Alan Melville and Charles Zwar Savoy Theatre London
    Abie’s Irish Rose by Anne Nichols Castle Square Theatre Boston
    Anna Lucasta by Philip Yordan His Majesty’s Theatre London
    Calumet Players’ Presentation
    The Gold Tooth by Andrew Lytle
    Greatness by Hale Sahneberger
    The Harvesters by Richard West
    Shadows by Tom Griscom
    Casino de Paris
    Little Lambs Eat Ivy by Noel Langley Ambassadors Theatre London
    The Paragon by Roland and Michael Pertwee Fortune Theatre London
    The Rivals by Richard Brinsley Sheridan Orpheum Theatre N
    Spider’s Web by Agatha Christie Savoy Theatre London
    Traveller’s Joy by Arthur MacRae Criterion Theatre London
    Watch on the Rhine by Lillian Hellman Ryman Auditorium N
    You and I by Philip Barry Little Theatre Birm’gham
    Swan Song by Ben Hecht and Charles MacArthur Nashville Community Playhouse N
    Three Scenes from Three Operas starring Salvatore Baccaloni
  - Newspaper Clippings, Librettos, Pamphlets, Playbills, Miscellaneous (Box 5)
    Programs (ca. 1913-16) Theatre Vendome N
  - Newspaper clippings on theatre (Box 5)
  - Newspaper clippings of New York Times Shakespeare Tercentenary editions and a special edition of Stratford-upon-Avon Herald. (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Pamphlets on theatre organizations and their histories (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous Materials (Box 5)
    History of Nashville, A. L. Crabb reports; [Mitchell’s] notes on theatre; undated Francis Robinson press release
  - Libettos (Box 5)
    Rigoletto by Verdi (published by Oliver Ditson)
    L’Oracolo by Camillo Zanoni (Scotti Grand Opera Co., published by Fred Rullman)
    The Jewels of the Madonna by Ermanno Wolf-Ferrari (published by G. Schirmer)
    Rigoletto by Verdi (published by Charles E. Burden)
    La Traviata by Verdi (published by Oliver Ditson)
    La Boheme by Puccini (Boston Grand Opera Season 1915-16, published by Charles E. Burden)
  - Playbills given by Herschel Gower (Box 5)
- (1965)
  - (Box 5)
    Macbeth by Shakespeare Edinburgh Int. Festival Church of Scotland Assembly Hall Edinburgh
    Poets in Public Edinburgh Int. Festival Freemason’s Hall Edinburgh
    There Was a Man: A New Play about Robert Burns by Tom Wright Morton House Edinburgh
    Beyond the Fringe, a revue by Alan Bennett, Peter Cook, Jonathan Miller, Dudley Moore May Fair Theatre London
    Four Thousand Brass Halfpennies, adapted’ from Dryden’s “Amphittyon” by Bernard Miles Mermaid Theatre London
    Half a Sixpence by Beverly Cross and David Heneker Broadhurst Theatre NY
    Portrait of a Queen by William Francis Vaudeville Theatre London
    Emlyn Williams as Charles Dickens Globe Theatre London
    Two Programs in German: “Porgy and Bess” by Gershwin and ‘ dame Butterfly” by Puccini
    London Theatre Guide, September 6-September 11, 1965
    Musical Concert by Marlene Dietrich Edinburgh Int. Festival Royal Lyceum Theatre Edinburgh
    A Program of various plays (Program printed in Greek, English, French and German) Epidaurus Theatre Greece
    An Edinburgh Fancy by the Royal Scottish Country Dance Society Royal High School Hall Edinburgh
    Edinburgh Int. Festival Program Edinburgh
    Festival Fringe Society Program Edinburgh
    A Festival in the Royal Mile by the Saltire Society Gladstone’s Land Edinburgh
    Inaugural Service of Thanksgiving and Dedication for the Edinburgh Int. Festival St. Giles’ Cathedral Edinburgh
    Johnny So Long by Vivienne C. Welburn Traverse Theatre Club Edinburgh
    Lysistrata by Aristophanes Edinburgh University Theatre Edinburgh
    Music of Georgian Edinburgh by the Saltire Society Gladstone’s Land Edinburgh
    Souvenir Programme, Edinburgh International Festival
- No Date
  - (Box 5)
    The Burn by Kerry Lee Oxford Theatre Group
  - Photographs, many of which are unidentified, of theatrical performers (Box 6)